eccouncil.org 2019-12-09

# Privacy Policy | EC-Council

EC-Council is committed to protecting your privacy and developing technology that gives you the most powerful and safe online experience. This Statement of Privacy applies to the EC-Council website and governs data collection and usage. By using the EC-Council website, you consent to the data practices described in this statement. At EC-Council, the privacy and security of our customers, respondents, and visitors are of paramount importance. EC-Council is committed to protecting the data you share with us.

**What Personal Information Does EC-Council Gather?**

EC-Council, through various web-platforms that help our members to register, reset passwords, get training, partner with us, etc. collects personally identifiable information such as e-mail addresses, names, home or work addresses, telephone numbers, organization names, etc. EC-Council also collects anonymous demographic information, which is not unique to you, such as your ZIP code, age, gender, preferences, interests, and favorites.

**Information You Give Us**

You may choose to apply for specific information or services on topics such as products, training, white papers, brochures, etc. which may require you to fill out forms and share your personal information. This information is irrespective of your membership. EC-Council asks you to allow representatives of EC-Council to contact you for the purpose asked.

**Data You provide to Us:**

EC-Council may collect different data from or about you depending on how you use EC-Council Services. Below are some examples to help you better understand the data we collect.

When you create an account and use the Services, including through a third-party platform, we collect any data you provide directly, including, but not limited to data about your accounts on other Services. We may obtain certain information through your social media or other online accounts if they are connected to your EC-Council account. If you login to EC-Council via Facebook or join EC-Council sponsored WhatsApp Group, another third-party platform or service, we ask for your permission to access certain information about that other account. For example, depending on the platform or service we may collect your name, profile picture, account ID number, login email address, location, physical location of your access devices, gender, birthday, and list of friends or contacts.

Those platforms and services make information available to us through their APIs. The information we receive depends on what information you (via your privacy settings) or the platform or service decide to give us.

If you access or use our Services through a third-party platform or service, or click on any third-party links, the collection, use, and sharing of your data will also be subject to the privacy policies and other agreements of that third party.

**Automatic Information**

We receive and store certain types of information whenever you interact with us. For example, like many websites, we use cookies and we obtain certain types of information when your web browser accesses eccouncil.org or any of our subdomains, advertisements, and other content served by or on behalf of eccouncil.org on other websites. We may use this information for internal analysis and to provide you with location-based services, such as advertising, search results, and other personalized content.

**E-mail Communications**

To help us make emails more useful and interesting, we often receive a confirmation when you open email from eccouncil.org, if your computer supports such capabilities. We also compare our customer list to lists received from other companies in an effort to avoid sending unnecessary messages to our customers. If you do not want to receive e-mail or other mail from us, please edit your customer communication preferences.

**Information from Other Sources**

We might receive information about you from other sources and add it to our account information.

By using or continuing to use the site you agree to our use of your information (including sensitive personal information) in accordance with this Privacy Notice, as may be amended from time to time by eccouncil.org at its discretion. You also agree and consent to us collecting, storing, processing, transferring, and sharing information (including sensitive personal information) related to you with third parties or service providers for the purposes as set out in this Privacy Notice.

We may be required to share the aforementioned information with government authorities and agencies for the purposes of verification of identity or for the prevention, detection, investigation, prosecution, or punishment of cyber incidents or offenses. You agree and consent to EC-Council to disclose your information if required under applicable law.

EC-Council encourages you to review the privacy statements of websites you choose to link to from EC-Council so that you can understand how those websites collect, use, and share your information. EC-Council is not responsible for the privacy statements or content on websites outside of the EC-Council family of websites.

**How EC-Council Uses Such Information**

EC-Council collects and uses your personal information to operate the EC-Council website and deliver the services you have requested. EC-Council also uses your personally identifiable information to inform you of other products or services available from EC-Council and its affiliates. EC-Council may also contact you via surveys to conduct research about your opinion of current services or of potential new services that may be offered. Some of the ways we may use personal information include:

Delivering a product or service you have requested.

Analyzing, supporting, and improving our products and your online experience.

Personalizing websites, newsletters, and other communications.

Administering and processing your certification exams.

Sending communications to you, including for marketing or customer satisfaction purposes, either directly from EC-Council or from our external partners.

**Website Visitors**

EC-Council may collect, record, and analyze information from visitors to our websites. We may record your IP address and use cookies. Furthermore, EC-Council may collect and process any personal data that you volunteer to us via our website forms, such as when you register for events or sign up for information and newsletters. This data is used to deliver customized content and advertising within EC-Council to customers whose behavior indicates that they are interested in a subject area. If you provide EC-Council with your social media details, EC-Council may retrieve publicly available information about you from social media.

**Information We Share**

EC-Council does not sell, rent, or lease your personal information to third parties.

EC-Council shares personal information in the following ways:-

EC-Council may, from time to time, contact you on behalf of external business partners about a particular offering that may be of interest to you. In those cases, your unique, personally identifiable information (e-mail, name, address, telephone number) is not transferred to the third party. However, EC-Council may share data with trusted partners to help us perform statistical analysis, send you email or postal mail, provide customer support, or arrange for deliveries. All such partners are prohibited from using your personal information except to provide these services to EC-Council, and they are required to maintain the confidentiality of your information.

EC-Council websites will disclose your personal information, without consent, only if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on EC-Council or the site; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of EC-Council; and, (c) act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of EC-Council or the public.

**Sensitive Personal Information**

EC-Council does not collect, use, or disclose sensitive personal information, such as race, religion, or political affiliations without your explicit consent.

**How EC-Council Stores the Information It Collects**

EC-Council stores your personally identifiable information such as name, contact number, email address, etc. on a secure server which is encrypted and is accessible only to EC-Council’s web applications such as our member portal (Aspen), eccouncil.org, and not any other third party websites or applications.

**How EC-Council Secures Your Information**

We take appropriate technical and organizational measures to secure your information and to protect it against unauthorized or unlawful use and accidental loss or destruction, including:

Only sharing and providing access to your information to the minimum extent necessary, subject to confidentiality restrictions where appropriate, and on an anonymized basis wherever possible;

Using secure servers to store your information;

Verifying the identity of any individual who requests access to information prior to granting them access to information; and

Using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) software or other similar encryption technologies to encrypt any payment transactions you make on or via our website.

Retention of Personal Information

We will retain your personal information as needed to fulfill the purposes for which it was collected. We will retain and use your personal information as necessary to comply with our business requirements, legal obligations, resolve disputes, protect our assets, and enforce our agreements.

**Opt-Out Policy**

If you would like to opt-out of the sharing of your personally identifiable information submitted on our website with third parties, contact us at https://visitor.constantcontact.com/do?p=un&m=001XlCQhv-8-iLcKU7k5J5FEQ%3D%3D&ch=62db10c0-e87d-11e8-aa96-d4ae52754dbc&ca=64594103-afdf-40e7-b759-3a4e2ac9bb73  and indicate your unwillingness to share such information with third parties.

If you would like to opt-out of receiving any direct marketing information from us, contact us (link to the contact page/email id) and indicate that you do not consent to the use by EC-Council of your personally identifiable information for marketing purposes.

**Cookie Policy**

**What is a “Cookie”?**

A cookie is a small text file sent by a web server and stored by the website on your computer to let the web browser keep track of information about your browsing on that site. Cookies are useful in helping the web browser remember specific information about your preferences, location, session details, etc. You can go to the preference or content setting of your web browser to delete the cookies pertaining to any website at any time.

**EC-Council Cookies**

At EC-Council, we give you the option to opt-out of cookies in order to let you control your privacy. Though we do recommend that for a good web experience, you allow EC-Council to store cookies.

**Turn Off or Opt-Out of Cookies**

Rejecting cookies may restrict your browsing experience on EC-Council websites related to important features such as login, location-specific data, and other demography-dependent info.

EC-Council does not share cookie information with any other website nor do we sell this data to any third party.

**Children’s Online Privacy**

EC-Council’s courses and services are not directed to children and EC-Council does not knowingly collect online personal information from children under the age of 13. If you are a parent or guardian of a minor under the age of 13 and believe that he or she has disclosed personal information to us, please contact us.

**Updates to this EC-Council Privacy Statement**

EC-Council will occasionally update this Statement of Privacy to reflect company and customer feedback. EC-Council encourages you to periodically review this Statement to be informed of how EC-Council is protecting your information.

**Contact Information**

EC-Council welcomes your comments regarding this Statement of Privacy. If you believe that EC-Council has not adhered to this Statement, please contact EC-Council at legal@eccouncil.org. We will use commercially reasonable efforts to promptly determine and remedy the problem.
